Morris Kyalo

P.O. Box 1996-90100, Machakos SIM No.: +254799799828

Email: mauricekyallo@gmail.com Portfolio: https://morriskyalo.github.io

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Date of Birth: 1st September 1999

Nationality KenyanID No. 36760699

CAREER PROFILE

A highly competent graduate of Diploma in Information and Communication Technology; 1+ years of experience in the ICT department - installing and maintaining software and hardware systems, networking, web design and data entry-user role. Critical thinker, and problem-solver through teamwork and communication.

Further expertise in tutoring, research, graphics design, and forex trading.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Information and Communication Technology (KNEC)

Machakos Institute of Technology

Sep 2017 - Jan 2021

• Graduated with, Credit

Computer Packages
Machakos Institute of Technology

March - May 2017

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Kabaa High School

• Mean grade attained, C

2013 - 2016

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- High integrity, and dependable
- Able to adapt to new environments, and self-driven
- Innovative, and results-oriented
- Team worker
- Flexible to tight work schedules

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Website, Apps, UI/UX, and Database Design & Development
- Graphics Design (Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Gimp)
- Network Management (IP addressing, Switching & Routing) CCNA Curriculum Material
- Programming (PHP, C++, ASP.Net, Ruby | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sass, Jekyll)
- Proficient in WordPress
- Systems Analysis & Requirement gathering
- Basics of Android Development
- Basics of Digital Transmissions
- Basics of Artificial Intelligence and Office Automation framework

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

New Birth Institute of Professional Studies Designation: Part-time ICT Tutor (5pm-7pm)

Feb 2022 to date

• Tutoring Module II Diploma-ICT students through 6 Units tested by the KNEC

Machakos County Government (PSQM & ICT) Designation: Intern

Feb 2021 to date

• Installing and maintaining software and hardware systems, networking, web design and data entry-user role. Troubleshooting inefficiencies from officers' PCs, and real-time communication on the recommended software and hardware upgrades

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Coding and development
- Networking
- Building DIY computer hardware systems
- Playing Lawn tennis

REFEREES

Please feel free to contact the under mentioned concerning my abilities, competencies, and work ethics;

Anthony Kilonzo

Principal ICT Officer

Machakos County Government

P.O. Box 1996-9010 Machakos

SIM No.: +254725226881

Phillip Biego

Deputy Principal
Machakos Institute of Technology
P.O Box 2069-90100, Machakos

SIM No.: +254754780447